# Saravanan Kalimuthu

## Software Engineer

✓ sathishdaywalker@outlook.com

+91 979-087-0737

PortFolio

## in LinkedIn



## Summary

Around and almost 5 years of experience in java development & used various technologies to develop API's and solutions. Having a great debugging skills and a fast learner who is proeficient in different frameworks and other languages

## Relevant Experience

SDE2 @Aditi, Inc/PayPal Client

May 2021- Present

Part of the PayPal Invoicing-Geo team. Individual contributions on External payments API and invoking Cross-Geo calls. Worked on the microservices and AMQ, Docker, Jenkins and GCP. Wrote the unit test cases. Involved in the impact analysis of key material changes. Wrote a abstract layer to prevent duplicate code. Wrote all the use cases and tested. Implemented a Cross-Geo feature in external payment without breaking the core functionality.

## Software Engineer @Assetpulse, Inc

Oct 2019 - May-2021

Hands-on experience in Spring-Web, Spring-JPA, Rest-Api's, WebSockets, Gradle, NPM.Involved in re-architecture of the existing product. Test Driven Development able to cover up to 96% of the lines. Having a deep understanding and the importance of code quality, continuously using the SonarQube to reduce cognitive complexity and code smell. Used various design patterns such as Adapter, Command and Builder.

#### Software Developer @Wellspring Software Labs

Feb 2018 - Sep 2019

Proficiently implemented Design patterns, data structures, and algorithms.Involved in design and development for validating/save master data.Involved in writing tests to log metrics for performance improvements.Wrote and delivered code on time with 92% of efficiency.Worked in China(Shenzhen) for 2 months and provided deployment support.

## Software Engineer @CoreNett Technologies

Jun 2016 - Dec 2017

Involved in the design and implementation using Java, J2EE 1.4[Servlets, JSP, EJB, DAO, Action] JavaScript1.2, HTML, CSS.Implement the change requests, along with the application development.Individually worked on Operations Module. It's used for ASM, TSO, Distributor, Retailer, Transaction, and Registration. Also individually worked on the Reports and Map module too. It Contains reports on every master programs.Involved in Unit testing.

## **Projects**

#### **Utils-Commons** in Java

https://github.com/sarvarunajvm/utils-commons

Collected and solved the common utilities which we face while coding this library will help the developer to avoid the code smells and repetative codes. This library was inspired based on the "Apache Commons IO". This library contains String, Number, Date, Set, List, BLOB & Zip.

## Port-Advancer in NodeJS

https://github.com/sarvarunajvm/port-advancer

A Simple tool that will help you to do the portforwarding and reverse proxieing based on the settings.json. This tools is specifically designed to solve the problem to override the organisation restrictions.

## vue-embed-gist in JavaScript/Vue

https://github.com/sudhanshu-15/vue-embed-gist/pull/13

Contibuted to an open source VueJs plugin to embed GitHub Gist in VueJs applications on NPM, with average 270 downloads/week. Implemented continuous integration and deployment on Github workflows. Npm: http://goo.gl/Hjkx2j

## Tools and technologies.

## **Coding Languages:**

Java8, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, JSON,XML, Python.

## Frameworks/Systems:

Spring, Vue, Vuetify, Hibernate,

Junit, NodeJS.

#### **Build Tools:**

Gradle, NPM, Maven.

#### **Source Control Systems:**

Git, GitHub, GitLab.

#### **Databases:**

Oracle, Postgres, Mysql, H2, SqLite.

#### IDE's and Operating Systems:

Eclipse, IntelliJ, VS-Code,

Windows/Linux.

#### Others:

Jira, Postman.

## Education

MCA @University of Madras 2016 - 2019

Graduated with 6.48 CGPA.

Designed and developed a cloud-based service that allows users to authenticate and make their data secure in the cloud using double encryption with the safe key.

**BCA** @Gurunanak College 2011 - 2014

Graduated with 6.24 CGPA.

Member of the National Honor
Society.Designed and developed
a webpage for internal exams.

## **Interests**

Technology, Swimming, Music, Competitive Video Games, Open source projects, Automation.

#### Skills and Abilities

Problem solving, Application design, Usability principles, Automation, Design Patterns, Vulnerability analysis, Data Structures and Algorithms, Team player, Quick learner